#### **Personal Information**

Name: Long Liang

Phone Number: 02885223642

Email Address: lianglongll1990@163.com

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/long-liang-0b8b03142/

### **Personal Statement**

I'm Master of Information Technology, with 10 years software development experience. Covers front-end, back-end, server operation and maintenance, data analytics, big data and other technologies. I'm adaptable and responsive and have a passion for learning technology. Wish to work as a full stack development engineer. Lifelong learning, continuous improvement.

#### Skill

Programming languages: Java、Shell、Python、Scala、SQL、JavaScript、C#.

Frontend components: JS、JSP、HTML、React.

Backend components: Spring、MyBatis、Dubbo、Redis、MangoDB、Node.Js.

Big data ecology: CDH、HDP、Hadoop、Spark、HBase、Doris、Kafka、Hue、Kylin、Superset.

Data governance: Metadata management, blood relationship, data quality management.

Machine learning: SparkMLLib、sk-learn、TensorFlow、Mahout.

IDE & AI: IDEA, Cursor, Trae, VS Code, Copilot, Tongyilingma.

### **Training and Certification**

AWS Academy Graduate - AWS Academy Cloud Architecting - 2024

Alibaba Tianchi Precision Medical Competition (with 43th in the final round and 2522 individuals or teams participating) - 2016

Udacity Machine Learning Advanced Training - 2014

#### **Education**

2024-07~current Master's degree at the University of Auckland - Information Technology 2020-03~2022-07 Bachelor's degree at China University of Petroleum - Computer Science and Technology

### **Work Experience and Project**

# China Shanghai Jiuyu Software Systems Co., Ltd.

April 2023 ~ July 2024.

Role: Architect.

**Project:** Shanghai traffic card PB-level data center, construction of BI report system, responsible for the overall system design, development, team communication and coordination. The front and back end projects are built using React+Spring. Data warehouses are built around the Hadoop ecosystems for storage and computing. Data warehouse adopts a hierarchical design model.

## China Shanghai FirstBrave Information Technology Co., Ltd.

September 2021 ~ September 2022.

Role: Architect.

**Project:** Build BI report system. Design and develop offline/real-time data warehouse, complete the calculation of indicators in each dimension, and provide business data monitoring and alarm. Optimize platform architecture to improve storage and IO efficiency.

### China Shanghai Wm-motor Technology Group.

May 2018 ~ August 2021.

Role: Architect.

**Project:** Responsible for the construction of PB-level data warehouse and real-time computing system. Build your data center around the Hadoop and Spark ecosystems. Cost reduction and efficiency increase: Migrate cold data to object storage to reduce storage

costs. Optimize HDFS and HBase high availability architectures to improve data processing efficiency. Cloud server optimization, reduce costs by 50%, improve IO efficiency by 6 times, storage capacity by 22 times.

## China Shanghai Liangxin Network Technology Co., Ltd.

February 2016 ~ April 2018.

**Role: Senior Software Engineer.** 

**Project:** Responsible for the design and development of financial lending system user, activity module full stack development. The front and back ends are built using JQuery+JSP+Spring.

# China Shanghai Hanzhiyou Information Technology Service Co., Ltd.

July 2012 ~ January 2016.

**Role: Software Engineer.** 

**Project:** Responsible for the full stack development of user module, coupon module and supplier management module of e-commerce platform. The frontend and backend are built using Bootstrap+JSP+Spring.